The true flow, orderly yet free,
can be neither stopped nor controlled.
In like fashion, this sturdy lock, too,
shall disperse to its original flow.
Away.
I shun thee away, force that acted as lock.
Now then, can I bring her back
without waking her up?
~ Pride of the Past ~
Magdalsia    Farmland Nation South of Tuldarr
My king!
King Hubert!
Hubert    King of Magdalsia
Someone!
Someone, come at once!
King Hubert of Magdalsia
has mysteriously fallen into a coma.
He remains unconscious,
despite no apparent abnormalities,
so they suspect magic.
I won't be able to tell
unless I take a look myself.
Should we have an envoy investigate the matter?
No, it'd be too dangerous
given what little we know.
I'll be the one to go.
Your Majesty will visit in person?
What if it's a trap?
I'll have people accompany me.
The most important person
in Tuldarr right now is Legis.
I'm nothing but a temporary ruler.
Understood.
But please let the king of Farsas
know before you depart.
Ugh, seriously?
The very thought makes me sad.
Isn't it better than having him
find out and get angry?
So that sums it up.
I'll be off to Magdalsia no—
"That sums it up," my foot.
Listen here.
It's almost the new year,
with just over a month until our wedding.
Why must you stick your nose
in this fishy business?
They're the ones who asked us.
Ignore them. Don't go.
I-I can't do that.
Magdalsia is Tuldarr's neighbor.
Time is of the essence with a life at stake.
I'll just go and take a look.
How much trouble have you gotten
yourself into doing exactly that?
You let me know beforehand,
so I'll consider that progress.
Make sure you take your spirits.
So I can go, then?
It's an affair that involves Tuldarr, isn't it?
I have no right to stop you.
I'll be back before you know it.
Thank you so much!
I swear, she really is a child.
Senn. Senn?
That's strange. There's no way!
A spirit can't ignore
a summons from Lady Tinasha.
That goes against the contract!
Wh-What now?
Could something have happened to him?
The contract is still in place,
so I don't think he's dead.
Itz, Karr, Saiha.
Can you go look for Senn?
My apologies for having you come all this way.
Gemma    Queen of Magdalsia
We can't figure out what could have caused it.
It's no trouble at all.
It is part of Tuldarr's duties
to resolve magic-related issues.
Who might you be?!
You're intruding in here without my consent!
How do you do, Gemma?
There's no need to concern yourself
with the king's health.
He's only sleeping.
I demand to know who you are!
My name is Lucia.
Lucia
I'm here to act as a proxy
while the king is asleep.
A proxy?
No, this can't be!
You can see that's the king's handwriting.
I've been given full power and authority.
If His Majesty really is safe,
I'd like for him to tell me what's going on!
Get out of here!
Gemma, do you not understand your situation?
Gasparo!
Have this woman removed at once!
Your Majesty, I'm afraid I can't do that.
Lady Lucia currently holds
the power of the throne.
Why, I never!
Men, escort the queen to her chambers.
S-Stop right there!
There you have it.
I know you've just arrived,
but please take your leave.
Will you not let me meet the king?
The king is still too unwell
to see the queen of Tuldarr.
I'll be leaving for today.
I look forward to meeting
again in the near future.
Do forgive me for being a poor host.
I don't know if that letter of proxy
was really written by the king,
but that woman is bad news.
Her magic rivals mine, or that of a witch.
What?
I didn't expect to run into someone so shady.
I bet Oscar will get mad at me again.
Good grief.
Rivaling that of a witch?
You really met such a human?
To be precise, Lady Tinasha
has more magical power,
but that's not the only measure
of someone's strength.
I think retreating for now was the right move.
I wonder if her goal is
to take over the country.
You think so?
It looked like those soldiers
were under her mind control.
If so, she can take control in no time at all.
I'm stumped.
Just as the year's about to end...
I do think we need to get rid of her.
Do you now?
Since she's so powerful, I'll need to
come up with a plan to take her on.
She was a bona fide human, though.
She couldn't really be a witch, right?
There currently exist
three witches in this world.
If we exclude the Witch of Silence, who
we know is the king of Farsas' grandmother,
that leaves two witches.
The Witch of the Water
and the Witch of the Forbidden Forest.
I've never met either of them.
You might be able to narrow it down
if you ask all the spirits.
The Witch of the Water
uses invisible spells, right?
Or so they say.
The Witch of the Forbidden Forest,
on the other hand, uses psychological magic.
They both sound awful.
Oh, right, Oscar.
What is it?
Do you know the story of Akashia
and the first queen of Farsas?
No.
There are no records left from that period.
They must have been lost at some point in time.
They say the first queen
gave Akashia to the founding king.
That's news to me.
All I know about Akashia is that an inhuman
being pulled it out of the Lake of Silence.
Who in the world told you that story?
A Farsas royal who studied abroad
in Tuldarr four hundred years ago.
Our family has a long history
of eccentric characters.
I'm not sure how reliable that story is.
I'll go get my clothes.
No, this suits me just fine.
I'll stop if you want me to.
Now's your chance.
You don't need to stop...
That said, Oscar...
What?
Let me say this first, since I feel like
you'll be mad if I don't.
Out with it.
I-I think I'm going to have to fight
someone as strong as a witch.
Go put on some clothes.
We can talk after you do.
Um, it's fine, really.
Without my chastity, I would need
a lot more power to use spirit magic...
I've got plenty of magic anyway—
Go get dressed!
I was the one being dumb and reckless.
I'm sorry.
Am I going to spend my whole life
without making love to her?
So did you try asking
all the spirits whether she's a witch?
That's the thing.
One of the spirits knows
the Witch of the Forbidden Forest,
but he's currently gone missing.
Gone missing?
That raises the chances that this woman
is the Witch of the Forbidden Forest.
You think so?
When two events happen at the same time,
you should suspect that they're related.
If that missing spirit was still here,
you could know whether she was
the Witch of the Forbidden Forest.
I suppose that's true.
Could Tuldarr have some remaining
records of the witches?
Even if we find out their
names or appearances,
there are no records left of their practices.
Leonora, the witch I killed, was only
first recorded after she had died.
I see.
The only others who might know are Travis,
as well as Lavinia, as a fellow witch.
I'll try reaching out to Lavinia.
Don't go asking Travis.
What? Are you sure?
I'm sure it'll be fine.
If she makes any moves, let me know at once.
What about a preemptive attack?
You can't be serious...
Why not?
A witch can wage war
against an entire country by herself.
If she intends to mobilize the nation
and start a war, we can't let that happen.
We should strike before she's fully prepared.
I understand your logic, but it
won't be pretty if we cross that line.
It could affect the entire mainland.
You...
Anyway, that's a no.
You always go overboard.
Got it.
You never run out of annoying enemies, huh?
Your Majesty, the new year festivities
went off without a hitch.
Yeah.
The Gandona Founding Day
celebrations are in two weeks,
with Queen Tinasha's abdication
and your wedding two weeks after that.
Sure is a hectic schedule.
But it's out of our hands.
You can retire for the night.
Sure.
You can go back as well.
You noticed me?
It felt like I was being watched.
Are you acting on Tinasha's orders?
Yep.
Did you find that missing spirit?
Not a trace.
How dare he go off on his own
and worry Lady Tinasha?
That aside, I received a reply
from Lavinia about the witch.
The description matches that of
the Witch of the Forbidden Forest.
Her name is Lucrezia.
It really was her!
This sucks.
It says here that she shows
no interest in politics.
I wonder what could have changed her mind.
Humans change all the time,
so this is no different.
The part I can't stand is the fact
that she uses psychological magic.
I'll be leaving.
I don't stand a chance against
her psychological spells, huh?
What a headache.
I didn't expect a barrier inside
the mirror, resulting in all this.
That's what you get for being greedy.
I'm so sorry.
It seems only half the mirror activated.
Leaving us with our unlikely ruler.
You had it coming.
Well, it'll be fine.
I have many schemes at hand.
Let's go ahead with this one first.
Your Majesty!
What is this before me?!
Oh, we received it as a gift for the new year.
Feel free to enjoy it.
A-Are you sure?
Don't be shy.
I'm not one for sweets, anyway.
In that case, I'll dig right in!
That said, I want you to work
twice as hard after you eat that...
Lazar?!
This magic circle really is well-made.
I see that it mostly maintains
its form with minimal magic,
and it amplifies upon activation
by absorbing the magic around it.
Thank you very much.
I wanted to send mages to areas
they haven't been deployed,
and this is what I came up with.
You might be able to apply this
for hidden magic circles.
Queen Tinasha, I thought you were here
to discuss wedding plans.
Oh, it completely slipped my mind.
Oscar, are you in... here...
Oscar!
Itz! Make sure Lazar is okay!
That's a relief.
This spell structure and this hex...
I've come across it somewhere...
Where's Akashia?
I was tricked!
Itz!
Keep an eye on these two!
I'll be right back!
Was there always a door here?
There's all sorts of
unexpected happenings this time.
Well, then...
Ow, that smarts.
Any longer, and it might have
melted me down to the bone.
So this is why only royalty
can wield this sword.
Well now.
I should be safe to use
teleportation magic from here.
Long time no see.
Where do you think you're going?
My, oh my.
I didn't expect you to pick up on it.
Put that down on the ground.
And the same goes for you.
Now that's a proposition that turns me on.
But I have someone waiting for me.
Then die.
We will meet again soon,
Witch of the Azure Moon.
Witch of the Azure Moon?
How's Lazar?
He's doing well.
Doan is looking after him.
I see.
Valt must be the one responsible
for the attack on Legis.
Both of you had the same hex placed on you.
You almost fell into a coma like Legis did.
Luckily, I was familiar with the hex.
However, he did succeed
in making off with Eleterria.
I'm sorry.
Look here, Tinasha.
First, you saved my life.
Thank you.
Back in the Dark Age, a mistake
like this would mean the gallows.
Do you have any last words?
Sorry.
I should have been more cautious.
I'm usually the one getting
lectured, so this is kind of fun.
I really am glad that nothing
terrible happened to you.
Valt was after both halves of Eleterria,
so he probably won't use the orb right away.
On the other hand, we'll need to
tighten up security on the other orb.
Should we just destroy it?
We have no idea what that might do.
Will it be safe in the Tuldarr treasury?
I'd like to think so, but I can't help but
worry after the abnormal actions he took.
Valt is an expert at reading minds.
Perhaps not people in general,
but rather, it seems he knows
the two of us very well.
Isn't that because he infiltrated
Farsas Castle as Nephelli's attendant?
He even spoke with you.
He did, but it goes beyond
something so superficial.
His knowledge is more intimate.
Intimate?
It's probably the current me that he knows.
Which is why I can't continue like this...
Tinasha...
What is it?
Pleading for your life?
You really are planning to kill me.
That's not true.
We haven't even gotten married yet.
Fine, then.
If you kill me, do it after
our kids have grown up.
I'll consider it.
I've grown soft lately.
Especially after you got engaged.
But you've been that way
ever since you came to this age.
Or should I say you've become spineless?
It's refreshing when you're brutally honest.
But you know, she used to be
a nice, honest, and sweet little girl,
before her first coronation.
I couldn't still act like a child
after becoming queen.
It seems Valt has seen through me with
shocking clarity ever since we first met.
But he won't continue to do as he pleases.
Before my private life, I am a queen.
Your wish is our command.
Our one and only queen.
I'll face him with the side of me
he knows nothing about.
~ Once upon a Time with You ~